

# FULLSTACK ENGINEER

evanplaice@gmail.com

FullStack Developer (3+ years FTE, 10+ OpenSource). I'm an innovator at heart, not satisfied with the common or easy path. I'm seeking a role where I can dig deep and have a high degree of impact.

evanplaice evanplaice evanplaice evanplaice evanplaice evanplaice evanplaice

**SKILLS** 

FRONTEND HTML/CSS SCSS JAVASCRIPT TYPESCRIPT WEB-COMPONENTS REACT ANGULAR

QA/TESTING TAPEJS MOCHA JEST SELENIUM

CI/CD GH-ACTIONS CIRCLECI GITLABCI TRAVISCI

DEVOPS AWS DOCKER VAGRANT

BACKEND NODEJS EXPRESS

DESIGN INKSCAPE PHOTOSHOP ILLUSTRATOR MOCKUPS

DATABASE MYSQL MSSQL MONGO

## **EMPLOYMENT**

#### Author, Maintainer, Contributor, Open Source

2019-01-01 - 2020-01-01

Took a year hiatus to work on Open Source R&D new/emerging technologies

- Dev: Created the VanillaWC GitHub organization and published 14 web components
- Dev: Created the VanillaES GitHub oganization, published 4 libraries, and 3 CLI tools
- Dev: Landed the 'ESM Compatibility' RFC and PR into ESLint core
- Community: Participated on node/modules team planning ESM support for Node
- Community: Joined JSONResume as a Maintainer
- R&D: Established 'Best Practices' for working with standard Web Components
- R&D: Established 'Best Practices' for developing Universal JS libraries and tooling

#### JavaScript Engineer - 100% Remote, Coder Technologies Inc

2018-02-03 - 2018-09-18

Coder is a cloud-native IDE (Integrated Development Environment) based on VSCode

- Dev: Worked on the main product UI from the early alpha stages through product launch (Typescript)
- Dev: Scaffolded the VSCode plugin integration API (Typescript)
- Dev: Contributed to and polished the FrontEnd website UI leading up to launch (Typescript React)
- QA: Built out the E2E testing automation, including integration with CI/CD (Selenium)

#### Lead I&R Technician, WiseConnect Inc

2017-05-01 - 2017-11-01

WiseConnect specializes in Copper and FiberOptic telecommunications installation and support

- Leadership: Provided training, mentorship, and QA for the Denver team
- Tech/CS: Performed 1K+ install/repair jobs

### DISH I&R Technician, 24 Hour Alert Systems

2016-08-01 - 2017-05-01

24HR is a contract installation for DISH Network

• Tech/CS: Performed 1.5k+ install/repair jobs

Field Representative/SME - 100% Remote, Strike Group LLC

2011-04-01 - 2015-05-01

SG is a DVSOB certified DOD contractor. I represented MARCORSYSCOM ComCam for West Coast/Pacific AOR

- CS: Provided logistics and help/desk support for 11 units across 6 military bases
- Logistics: Fielded and tracked \$5+ million in visual imagery and military hardware
- Tech: Repaired Xerox MFDs, updated laptops (120+) quarterly, and administered the 3 TIPS networks
- · Leadership: Advised COMCAM Unit Chiefs/Officers and frequently led small teams of Marines
- · Leadership: Led semi-annual training sessions on TIPS (Tactical Imagery Production System) deployment
- Leadership: Fielded the TIPS on 3 training evolutions (ie large scale deployment exercises)
- Dev: Designed, built, and maintained company's online presence @ StrikeGroup.org
- · Dev: Automated processes to generate, verify, and distribute documentation and digital assets
- Credentials: Earned 2 Xerox MFD Certifications and acquired a 'Public Trust' clearance
- Awards: Received a 'Commendation for Exemplary Performance' for my role in DesertScimitar14

#### Principal Software Engineer - 100% Remote, JPA Inc (RIOS)

2008-07-01 - 2010-02-01

Co-Developed the RIOS for FedEx throughout all stages of planning and development

- · Product: Led product development from the PDR (Preliminary Design Review) thru Acceptance
- Arch: Designed the communications, systems, n-tier, and IPC (Inter Process Communications) architecture
- Dev: Build parsers for ARINC-424, the host datapool, and ported the floating-point conversion lib from C to C#
- Dev: Implemented a custom Layer 2 network protocol client/server for host interaction
- Dev: Implemented the database layer. Incl datapool, ARINC424, cache layer, queries, and stored procedures
- Dev: Build dynamic 2D projections to graph the Glideslope and ILS deviation plots
- Dev/Tech: Performed the onsite installation and host integration per the agreed (7 day) schedule
- Hardware: Specified and assembled the rackmount PC, backups, hot spares, and touchscreen displays
- QA: Worked on-site with the Check Pilot to integrate last-minute look-and-feel changes/fixes

#### Electrical IO Specialist, JPA Inc

2004-07-01 - 2008-07-01

Hacking on commercial full flight aircraft simulators for fun and profit

- Hardware: Designed, implemented, installed, and updated avionics instruments and systems. Incl EGPWS, TCAS,
- Hardware: Worked Electrical or Rigging for 5 Level D Flight Simulator Relocations and 2 door trainers
- Tech: Provided on-site support through the Level D FAA baseline certification of a 747-400
- Eng: Researched, red lined, and drew est 200+ electrical prints
- Dev: Designed, built, and maintained the company online presence

#### Flight Simulator Manufacturing Specialist, SATCO LLC

2003-12-01 - 2004-07-01

SATCO specialized in the manufacture of Level D FFS (Full Flight Simulator) and FTD (Fixed Training Devices)

• Hardware: Manufactured avionics cables, wiring harnesses, instrument panels

# **PROJECTS**

#### Founder - @VanillaWC (Organization)

2019-04-08 - 2020-02-07

Founded on organization to explore that development of standard web components.

• 14 Components Published

Web Components, Standards, JavaScript

#### Founder - @VanillaES (Organization)

2018-02-03 - 2020-02-07

Founded on organization to explore the development of ES modules for the web and Node.

- 4 Libraries Published

ECMAScript, Standards, Node

#### Individual Contributor - Coder.com (Application)

2018-02-05 - 2018-09-18

Like VSCode in the cloud. It's a fully featured cloud-native IDE based on Monaco.

Worked through product launch

JavaScript, Typescript, React, Selenium, Monaco

#### Author - ¡Query-CSV (Library)

2012-04-20 - 2020-02-07

The first RFC 4180 spec parser written for JavaScript

FOOL Chargeon Citllub

• 2 CLIs Published

- 500+ Stars on Github
- 500k+ Downloads

JavaScript, Parser

### Contributor - Packet.net (Library)

2010-12-28 - 2018-09-18

An open source framework for capturing, parsing, and formatting network packets

- Extended support for TCP, UDP, IPv4, IPv6
- Added IGMPv2, LLDP, Wake-on-Lan protocols
- Added/improved unit and performance tests

C#, NUnit, PCAP

#### Principal Developer - RIOS (Application)

2008-07-01 - 2010-02-01

An Instructor Operating Station (ie touchscreen Interface) for a 737-400 Flight Simulator

- Passed 3 9s of uptime over 3 months
- Full SDLC (Software Development Lifecycle)
- Implemented the multi-application IPC and data layers
- Built a custom Layer-2 networking protocol client/server

C#, MSSQL, Networking, Windows2K

## **EDUCATION**

#### Business CIS, Metro State University (Incomplete)

2006-08-17 - 2008-04-09

## **AWARDS**

#### Certificate of Commendation - United States Marine Corps

2014-06-30

Issued for exemplary performance In support of Desert Scimitar '14. Including directing the first successful deployment of the TIPS (Tactical Imagery Production System) 3.0 in a field environment.

# **INTERESTS**

**EXTREME SPORTS** 

SNOWBOARDING, WAKEBOARDING, ROCK CLIMBING